{
  "status": "success",
  "data": [
    {
      "question": "Convert the following sentence into complex/ He is poor, but he is happy.",
      "answer": "Though he is poor, he is happy",
      "arr": [
        "He is poor so he is happy.",
        "He is poor and he is happy.",
        "If he is poor he was happy"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What an idea' is an example of ------------- sentence.",
      "answer": "Exclamatory",
      "arr": ["Declarative", "Affirmative", "Interrogative"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Barking dog seldom bites is a/ an ------------ sentence.",
      "answer": "Simple",
      "arr": ["Compound", "Complex", "Compound-Complex"]
    },
    {
      "question": "The children looked at ------------- when surprise gifts were given.",
      "answer": "one another",
      "arr": ["either", "each", "neither"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Pick the adjective form of 'boy'",
      "answer": "boyish",
      "arr": ["boyhood", "boyous", " boys"]
    },
    {
      "question": "The harder you work, ----------- you will do.",
      "answer": "the better",
      "arr": ["the good", "better", "the best"]
    },
    {
      "question": "---------- of my classmates came to meet me when I was not well.",
      "answer": "Each",
      "arr": ["Either", "Any", "little"]
    },
    {
      "question": "The teacher gave sweets to the children. Pick the direct object from above sentence.",
      "answer": "Sweets",
      "arr": ["The teacher", "The children", "None of these"]
    },
    {
      "question": "The innocence of a child attract me. Hear the word 'innocence' is -------.",
      "answer": "Abstract noun",
      "arr": ["Proper noun", "Material noun", "Common Noun"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Among the two plans, I would prefer the former to the ---------.",
      "answer": "latter",
      "arr": ["later", "latest", "last"]
    },
    {
      "question": "My brother is not ------------- than me.",
      "answer": "older ",
      "arr": ["old", "elder ", "oldest"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Without any ----------- delay the guide helped us reach out hotel.",
      "answer": "further",
      "arr": ["far ", "farther", "furthest"]
    },
    {
      "question": "She is as smart as ----------.",
      "answer": "I am",
      "arr": ["me ", "mine ", "I"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Lead is the heaviest of all metals. Change it into coparative degree.",
      "answer": "Lead is heavier than all other metals.",
      "arr": [
        "All other metals are heavier than lead.",
        "Lead is heavier metal",
        "Lead is as heavy as all other metals."
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "There are millions of stars in ------- space.",
      "answer": "no article needed",
      "arr": ["a ", "an", "the"]
    },
    {
      "question": "She speaks ---------- Hindi language fluently.",
      "answer": "the",
      "arr": ["a", "an", "no article needed"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Don't fight each other, ------------?",
      "answer": "wiil you",
      "arr": ["do you", "won't you", "can't you"]
    },
    {
      "question": "It is high time they ------ here.",
      "answer": "reached",
      "arr": ["are reaching", "have reached", "reach"]
    },
    {
      "question": "They dislike ------------- time.",
      "answer": "wasting",
      "arr": ["to waste", "wasteing ", "wasted"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Do you mind -------------- me your pen to sign this document?",
      "answer": "giving",
      "arr": ["gave ", "given ", "will give"]
    },
    {
      "question": "You/ had better/ to stay at home./ no error",
      "answer": "to stay at home",
      "arr": ["You", "had better", "no error"]
    },
    {
      "question": "More than one attempt --------- been made to break the lock.",
      "answer": "has",
      "arr": ["have ", "were", "are"]
    },
    {
      "question": "One of my relatives ----------- been selected to the cricket team.",
      "answer": "has",
      "arr": ["were", "are", "have"]
    },
    {
      "question": "One of my firends who --------- been selected to the cricket team",
      "answer": "have",
      "arr": ["is ", "has", "was"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Everyboy and every girl --------- given a packet of sweets.",
      "answer": "was ",
      "arr": ["are", "were", "have"]
    },
    {
      "question": "I/ did not seen/ her for two weeks./ no error",
      "answer": "did not seen",
      "arr": ["I", "her for two weeks", "no error"]
    },
    {
      "question": "There ---------- a large number of weak boys in the class.",
      "answer": "is ",
      "arr": ["are", "were", "have"]
    },
    {
      "question": "The minister was accompanied ---------- his private secretary",
      "answer": "by",
      "arr": ["with", "to ", "on"]
    },
    {
      "question": "I cannot ----------- his nonsense.",
      "answer": "put up with",
      "arr": ["put on", "put off", "put up"]
    },
    {
      "question": "She is suspicious ----------- everyone who comes to her house.",
      "answer": "of ",
      "arr": ["on", "in ", "for"]
    },
    {
      "question": "They have been working here ---------- last year.",
      "answer": "since",
      "arr": ["for ", "from", "to"]
    },
    {
      "question": "It is time you --------- office.",
      "answer": "went",
      "arr": ["go", "come", "reach"]
    },
    {
      "question": "There will be a rush for seats when the train --------.",
      "answer": "arrives",
      "arr": ["will arrive", "arrived", "is arriving"]
    },
    {
      "question": "The old man was too weak to travel ------------- himself.",
      "answer": "by ",
      "arr": ["with", "for ", "Interrogative"]
    },
    {
      "question": "He died -------- his own hands.",
      "answer": "by",
      "arr": ["of ", "with", "in"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Sachin is very good player. In this sentence the wrod 'very' is ------.",
      "answer": "adjective",
      "arr": ["noun", "verb", "adverb"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Nobody knows ----- it really means.",
      "answer": "what",
      "arr": ["why", "if ", "how"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Phrasal verb with meaning 'visited",
      "answer": "called at",
      "arr": ["called up", "called by", "called for"]
    },
    {
      "question": "He used to play hockey, ----------?",
      "answer": "didn't he",
      "arr": ["don't he", "usedn't he", "doesn't he"]
    },
    {
      "question": "They ----------- Chennai last week.",
      "answer": "visited",
      "arr": ["have visited", "were visited", "visit"]
    },
    {
      "question": "I usually ---------- to temple every Sunday.",
      "answer": "go",
      "arr": ["goes", "went", "going"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Nobody ----------- permitted to enter the hospital so far.",
      "answer": "has been",
      "arr": ["have been", "were", "are"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Everybody has got a pass mark ------------?",
      "answer": "haven't they",
      "arr": ["hasn't they", "do they", "have they"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Practise --------- man perfect.",
      "answer": "makes",
      "arr": ["does", "is making", "made"]
    },
    {
      "question": "He is a man -------- everyone respects",
      "answer": "whom",
      "arr": ["who ", "whose", "which"]
    },
    {
      "question": "The pandemic condition has turned from bad to ----------------.",
      "answer": "worse",
      "arr": ["bad", "worst", "well"]
    },
    {
      "question": "If you hadn't come, I ------ angry with you.",
      "answer": "would have been",
      "arr": ["would be", "will be", "had seen"]
    },
    {
      "question": "\"Your memory surprises me\" change into passive voice.",
      "answer": "I am surprised at your memory",
      "arr": [
        "I am surprised by your memory.",
        "I was surprised by your memory",
        "I had been surprised by your memory"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Arun said \"where can I get an application form? Chose the right indirect speech",
      "answer": "Arun enquired where he could get an application form",
      "arr": [
        "Arun enquired whether he could get an application form",
        "Arun enquired where he got an application form",
        "Arun enquired where could he get an applicatin form"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": " ' I know him' convert into passive voice",
      "answer": "He is known to me",
      "arr": ["He is known by me", "He was known by me", "He was know to me"]
    },
    {
      "question": "He has good command --------------- English.",
      "answer": "of ",
      "arr": ["over", "in ", "on"]
    },
    {
      "question": "He take pride -------- his son.",
      "answer": "in",
      "arr": ["of ", "about", "for"]
    },
    {
      "question": " He gave me a gift' change into passive voice",
      "answer": "I was given a gift by him",
      "arr": [
        "A gift is given to me by him",
        "A gift was given to me by him",
        "I was given him a gift"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "She said, \"did you finish the wrok?\" convert the above sentence into direct speech",
      "answer": "She asked me if I had finished the work",
      "arr": [
        "She asked me did I finished the work.",
        "She asked me that I did finish the work.",
        "She asked if I had finish the work"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "The Teacher said that -------------",
      "answer": "The sun rises in the east",
      "arr": [
        "The sun rose in the east",
        "The sun has risen in the east",
        "The sun rise in the East"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "This is the matter ----------- I am  proud.",
      "answer": "of which",
      "arr": ["which", "that", "who"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Adjective form of 'man' is ----",
      "answer": "manly",
      "arr": ["manhood", "man", "men"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Neither principal  ---------- teachers will attend the meeting",
      "answer": "nor",
      "arr": ["or", "either", "and"]
    },
    {
      "question": "I have been waiting at the bus stop for the past 15 minutes",
      "answer": "How long have you been waiting?",
      "arr": [
        "Why are you standing here?",
        "How far you have been waiting?",
        "When you are waiting here?"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Scarcely had we got home --------------- it began to rain.",
      "answer": "when",
      "arr": ["then", "than", "but"]
    },
    {
      "question": "He is such an honest man ------------ everybody likes him",
      "answer": "that",
      "arr": ["as", "so", "and"]
    },
    {
      "question": "---------- you please tell me the truth!",
      "answer": "Would",
      "arr": ["will", "can", "should"]
    },
    {
      "question": "We -------- painting before it started raining",
      "answer": "had finished",
      "arr": ["finished", "finish", "have finished"]
    },
    {
      "question": "He is used to______ by metro",
      "answer": "travelling",
      "arr": ["travel", "travelled", "travels"]
    },
    {
      "question": "They visit Taj Mahal. change the sentence into past perfect",
      "answer": "They had visited Taj Mahal",
      "arr": [
        "They have visited Taj Mahal",
        "They have been visited Taj Mahal",
        "They visited Taj Mahal"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "No one was there,______? add tag",
      "answer": "were they",
      "arr": ["wasn’t they", "was they", "weren’t they"]
    },
    {
      "question": "He /wrote a letter/ in English language/ no error (choose the error part)",
      "answer": "in english language",
      "arr": ["he", "wrote a letter", "no error"]
    },
    {
      "question": "They/ are knowing /me/ no error  (choose the error part)",
      "answer": "are knowing",
      "arr": ["they", "me", "no error"]
    },
    {
      "question": "He/ forbade me to /not go there /no error  (choose the error part)",
      "answer": "not go there",
      "arr": ["he", "forbade me to", "no error"]
    },
    {
      "question": "A good man and useful citizen_____ passed away",
      "answer": "has",
      "arr": ["have", "are", "is"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Abhijeet Banerjee won_____ Nobel Prize in Economics",
      "answer": "the",
      "arr": ["an", "a", "no article needed"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Fortune______ The Brave",
      "answer": "favours",
      "arr": ["is favouring", "will favour", "favour"]
    },
    {
      "question": "_____You say so, I must believe it",
      "answer": "since",
      "arr": ["as", "so", "when"]
    },
    {
      "question": "The new secretary started work_____ last week",
      "answer": "from",
      "arr": ["since", "till", "to"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Only____ children like thrillers",
      "answer": "a few",
      "arr": ["the few", "a little", "few"]
    },
    {
      "question": "She was quite overcome______ emotion",
      "answer": "with",
      "arr": ["from", "of", "in"]
    },
    {
      "question": "______ of them Rose from their seats to protest",
      "answer": "all",
      "arr": ["each", "every one", "None of these"]
    },
    {
      "question": "It Looks ________ it is going to rain",
      "answer": "as if",
      "arr": ["if", "whether", "when"]
    },
    {
      "question": "We have to stay here_____ he comes",
      "answer": "until",
      "arr": ["when", "while", "during"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Noun form of ‘create’ is:",
      "answer": "creation",
      "arr": ["created", "creating", "creatory"]
    },
    {
      "question": "He Asked me....",
      "answer": "where my book was",
      "arr": ["where my book is", "where was my book", "where is my book"]
    },
    {
      "question": "The adjective form of ‘riches’ is",
      "answer": "rich",
      "arr": ["Richness", "Richly", "Richy"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Usha runs_____",
      "answer": "fast",
      "arr": ["fastly", "faster", "quick"]
    },
    {
      "question": "My father asked whether anyone — his purse? (Choose the correct verb form.)",
      "answer": "had seen",
      "arr": ["seen", "have been", "saw"]
    },
    {
      "question": "The rule is applicable — everyone.",
      "answer": "for",
      "arr": ["with", "to ", "of"]
    },
    {
      "question": "They speak English very good.Correct the sentence",
      "answer": "They speak English very well",
      "arr": [
        "They speak English well.",
        "They speak the English very good.",
        "They speak English very good"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "My uncle is working in a large office, —— my aunt is working at her home.",
      "answer": "whereas",
      "arr": ["actually", "firstly", "where"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Had I known this, ——.",
      "answer": "I would have kept him at a distance.",
      "arr": [
        "I would keep him at a distance",
        "I would have kept him at a distance.",
        "I will have kept him at a distance."
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "The old man —— lives in my neighbourhood is a University professor.",
      "answer": "who",
      "arr": ["whose", "whom", "which"]
    },
    {
      "question": "I was sitting —— an arm chair.",
      "answer": "in",
      "arr": ["on", "with", "at"]
    },
    {
      "question": "(Choose the right verb.) They —— down every afternoon after lunch.",
      "answer": "lie",
      "arr": ["lied", "lay", "am lying"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Many a cup and saucer —— been broken.",
      "answer": "has",
      "arr": ["have", "is making", "are"]
    },
    {
      "question": "They should be grateful if we ——— send them money.",
      "answer": "would",
      "arr": ["will", "may", "can"]
    },
    {
      "question": "There are plans to rebuild the town hall, but it ——— not happen for another five years.",
      "answer": "may",
      "arr": ["should", "do", "has"]
    },
    {
      "question": "He said, “I am leaving for Mumbai tomorrow”. (Report the sentence.)",
      "answer": "He said that he was leaving for Mumbai the next day.",
      "arr": [
        "He said he was leaving for Mumbai on the next day.",
        "He said that he is leaving for Mumbai the next day.",
        "He said that he is leaving for Mumbai on tomorrow."
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Write the verb form of ‘courage’.",
      "answer": "encourage",
      "arr": ["courageous", "couragness", "couraging"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Choose the correct sentence.",
      "answer": "Shama Passed the examination in 1980.",
      "arr": [
        "Shama was passed the examination in 1980.",
        "Shama had been passing the examination in 1980.",
        "Shama had passed the examination in 1980."
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Be quiet and listen to my words. (Report the sentence.)",
      "answer": "He urged them to be quiet and listen to his words.",
      "arr": [
        "He urged them and said to quiet and listen to his words.",
        "He urged that they should be quiet and listen to his words.",
        "He asked them to be quiet and listen to his words."
      ]
    }
  ]
}
